When creating Word documents, there will
be situations where you need to display
certain information in a table format.
Word has tools within itself
to allow you to do this.
And I'm going to demonstrate them here.
The first way to insert a table is
to go to the insert tab, click on
that, and then select the table icon.
And just below there, as I start
to move my mouse down the rows, and
then across, it automatically starts
to insert that amount of columns
and rows within to the letter.
When I'm happy with the number of
columns and rows I want just click
and it will automatically insert them.
The problem there is, is that I
still need to populate the table.
An alternative to this is importing
information from another document and
then converting that into a table.
The first thing I'm
going to do is undo that.
So that is now clear.
I will then open the spreadsheet that
I downloaded from the vision2learn
website, which contains the
information that I'm going to use.
So what I need to do is I need to
copy this information, so I'll click
and hold and drag it down and across,
and then select the copy icon.
Now that I have copied that
information, I can then go back
to the letter and select paste.
So as you can see it has now, pasted
the information into the letter.
I now have several options so if I click
on the little drop on the paste options
button, it gives me the option to keep
the source formatting, use the destination
styles, link and keep source formatting,
link and use destination styles, insert
as a picture or keep the text only.
For this example.
I'm going to keep the text only.
So as you can see, it has now
inserted that text into the letter.
But it isn't presented
in a very nice format.
What I need to do now is I need
to convert that text into a table.
To do that I need to highlight all of the
text and then go back to the insert tab.
So I click on insert and go to table
and then select convert text to table.
So Word is actually identifying
where the spacing is occurring
within each of those pieces of text.
And it's automatically identified
that it needs to have three
columns and eight rows.
It is separated by the tabs.
So I click OK, that will
insert the text into a table.
Once I have the information in the table,
I then want to apply some formatting.
If I double click on the icon
at the top left of the table, it
will open up the table design tab.
From there I can apply table
styles, shading, border styles,
variety of different things.
In this example, all I'm going
to do is just to add some
shading to the top border.
Once that's done, and I'm
happy that it looks okay, I
can then save if the document.